all right welcome to active infant
stream number 3.1 on systems it's August
31st
2024 as usual I'll begin it
with fetching the
origin committing many many updates
pushing
them and while that's writing here
what's going to happen we're going to be
talking about systems within systems and
also whatever else we end up exploring
touching upon some developments in the
code base related to William Blake Foya
Freedom of Information Act cognitive
sovereignty and the pmdp social
learning we'll start it off by making an
initial GitHub push I'll copy everything
down below so we can delete from here
GitHub push looks done let's reload the
repo double check it's there
and we see pushes now so we're triple
checked
live all right made the GitHub push in
this opening the purpose of this stream
or at least one of them is to explore
various views on implementations of and
interactions with systems let's start by
going through several code-based
developments that I've prepared to show
please at any time feel free to write in
the live chat a question or a comment or
idea so I'll go through these three and
then another fourth section at that
point conclude along the way or at the
end just write in the live chat if
anything is like off with what you're
seeing or if you have questions or
ideas okay we are in folder zero context
system systems and we'll start in the
William Blake
folder we're going to look at through
some code methods William Blake's
mentions of systems talk about some
relevances for modern systems design and
look at the applications in the codebase
okay so within the William Blake
folder there are several scripts and
there are several folders William Blake
resources contains files like additional
references just bibliography hundreds of
relevant
citations Blake's works by year and
table of contents to Erman then there's
the edman edited complete works of Blake
and letters which is 29,000 lines and
the PS which is 88,200
lines as a reminder in cursor all of the
code Bas indexed whatever the type is so
there's nothing to resync here let's
double check
though and I'm using cursor
4.3 so
40.3 okay so lot of ways to jump in the
poems are great and this is also just
the plain text this is not the
illuminated printing I'll start with the
Blake mentions dopy right click open in
the integrated
terminal Python 3
Blake mentions
py what this is going to do is look at
the Target terms in the top of the
document system that's our Focus but
also just to show that it's a little
more General arason and Los logging is
done and for each of the terms in the
Target
terms where the term is mentioned
ignoring
case three lines before and three lines
after get joined into a snippet and that
gets saved into an output file so here's
across that document of Erman which
there can be typos there can be all
other sorts of little textual artifacts
not everything's included not all the
works remained Etc ET Etc but we can
explore okay these are the mentions of
system in Blake there's nine of them
from this poll till a system was formed
Etc I must create a system or be
enslaved by another man
striving with systems to deliver
individuals from those
systems fixing their systems permanent
by mathematic power to govern the evil
by good and States abolish
systems and here Begins the system of
moral virtue named
Rahab no Grand work can have them they
produce system and
monotony before I begin engraving them
as it will enable me also to regulate a
system of working that will be uniform
from beginning to end so that's kind of
a cool way to jump in and noting that
there's many more mentions of these
characters Oris in and Los but same
principle applies these are just much
longer documents with
Snippets often it's like reading through
Blake there's all these entities all
these things are being mentioned and so
these two entity extraction methods use
a simpler method which is just basically
looking for capitalized this is a Rex
that finds basically capitalized words
single or pairs whether at a line start
or not that start with capitalization
and then it goes through and counts it
the entity extraction with Spacey uses
this package for for slightly more
advanced entity recognition but in any
case what these end up doing is they
output into the analysis
section these plots are
um just example
plots but we can see for example here's
a top 10 entities here's entity
frequency histogram and so this counts
the number of entities of of each time
that the entities are mentioned so it
kind of just sweeps through finds the
capitalized um and the analysis is just
doing some basic summary statistics on
that so that's just kind of a fun way to
jump in and explore how many entities
are done and just striving with
systems okay that's part one on William
Blake let's go to social sciences and
active
inference okay so this initially comes
from Andrew pasa's awesome work at the
IC
2s2 conference where he made a Workshop
active agents and active inference
approach to agent-based modeling in the
social sciences he made it in a Google
cab notebook which is awesome very
accessible and allows people to get
active inference multi-agent Network
learning simulations working in their
browser that's
awesome notebooks are again great for
just one click running in a browser
however they can get pretty unwieldy
because you have these linear documents
that can sprawl on and on and on and
it's hard to know what has been run and
not and so on and so uh 27 days ago I
made a contribution just to take his
collab notebook and copy it into a
single. py so that just took his great
as far as I understand manually written
code about 1,500 lines of code and just
brought it into a single python script
so it could be run as a script and then
what I did over the previous uh day or
two having some fun conversations with
Andrew in Discord is broke it up across
a bunch of different
scripts so there's a main.py this is
also it's more than just broken up
there's also many other changes and
developments sometimes to the point
where it was like just going through
hands and minds and AIS and it's like
wait what is even happening but this was
just a again experimental
play main calls all the aspects of the
simulation and then the utilities are
broken up across math data
analysis agents creating them in the
matrices and their
networks active inference such as the
active inference Loop itself and then
the the
visualizations this is pretty cool again
it's a really helpful imdp styled way to
work with what Andrew made which is this
awesome multi-agent communication
Network simulation there's agents in
subn networks and the output of this in
the current output folder there's a
couple methods that just visualize the
matrices of the different agents so a
matric that's a for ambiguity that Maps
between observations and hidden States
so here there's three observations and
then there's three hidden States if it
were perfect sensory recognition you'd
see only ones on the diagonals and zero
elsewhere that's when the partially
observable Markov process can be treated
as a fully observable Markov process B
is where action comes into play that's
where it becomes a Markov decision
process with a policy decision around
which slice of B to pick C is a vector
that describes preference that comes
into play with the pragmatic value in
the expected free energy calculations
and D is an initial prior on hidden
State e is the Habit Vector which
describes the prior probabilities on
action
selection F this is just showing the F
at the very beginning I think it just
given a tiny value for the variational
free energy just to make sure it's all
initialized and G not not sure what's
even happening here that's for expected
free energy for
planning and not that this was was tuned
or even really checked super deeply for
concurrence with the initial simulation
but these are uh Fitness of the
solutions of the agents across two
different graph
topologies here's a heat map looking at
the correlations of some summary
statistics of these simulations there's
average fitness Max Fitness and Min of
the agents and then Fitness improvements
the variables have of course to
correlation with himself but there's
some interesting
patterns here there is some sweeping
across error rate and C Improvement
preference learning a after every X time
steps distribution of Fitness
Improvement by network type again kind
of interesting possibly the case that
the small world Network leads to better
Fitness
improvements Fitness average fitness
over trials by network type here we see
the random and the small world and their
average fitness changing I think this
might reflect Why by the end of the 160
trials they have an equivalent average
fitness however the small world improves
more most improved topology and let's
see Max Fitness versus men Fitness just
a few scatter data points um the
simulation extensively logged and traced
and it's just really cool let's just try
so that we can explore a little bit on
the interpretability side crl a contrl
shift L that's going into the
sidebar and we'll ask
comprehensively explain this
simulation all the components and
methods all about how exactly active
inference is being being applied
here this is the sidebar chat one thing
I'm also out of fast request so I really
don't know how fast cursor is going to
process this control I this floating
composer window is an incredible
development it enables pretty easy
editing across multiple files which can
get really far ranging so it's defin
like a check and find out what's
happening but it can do some amazing
things and I think that later in the
Stream when we get to more code editing
we'll definitely be using the composer a
lot
okay the script sets up and runs a
simulation using active inference
principles it involves initializing
matrices creating an agent running
inference loops and visualizing results
the main components include logging
agent setup running simulations and
processing results we have Imports and
logging path setups and
constants
initialization Fitness data
initialization visualization and
inference Loop visualization full sweep
of the simulation full sweep simulation
runs a full sweep simulation across
multiple trials results processing final
visualization active inference
application active inference is applied
to the following steps One agent
initialization the agent is initialized
with matrices that represent its beliefs
about the world that's the joint
distribution agents are mapped
represented compositional cognitive
cartography about their beliefs about
observations hidden States and policies
action selection in the world the agent
runs an inference Loop where it updates
its beliefs and actions based on
observations and internal models three
learning and adaptation the agent adapts
its internal models as matrices based on
a learning parameters and observations
and four Sim ation and visualization and
now it's also pulling in real links to
Plus for example here and a medium
tutorial that is
all's medium tutorial from 2018 on
active
inference cool okay let's just go a
little bit further here we're using GPT
40 we can
ask how does the specific
implementation
of active inference here in
utils
uncore active
inference
differ from other agent based
models give comy tensive concise
answer also
conveying why slow slash where slash
when quote free
energy calculations are specifically
coming into
play it was a great question someone
brought up in the Institute Discord
pretty recently about what H how does
active inference differ from
embodiment haven't people been thinking
about about perception action in terms
of their Unity for a long time let's
kind of ask a VAR to that
question implementation of active
inference in the util script differs
from other agent-based models primarily
in the use of the free energy principle
to guide agent Behavior here's a
comprehensive yet concise explanation
key differences from other agent based
models one free energy
minimization agents minimize a quantity
called free energy which is a measure of
the difference between pred predicted in
actual sensory inputs this drives both
perception updating belief change your
mind and action selecting actions to
minimize future free energy expected
free energy change World other models uh
us them other models traditional
agent-based models often use predefined
rules heris discs or reinforcement
learning to guide agent Behavior two
regarding belief updating inactive
inference agents are continuously
updating their beliefs using Basi and
inference integrating new sensory data
to minimize the variational free energy
other models belief updating may not be
as Central or they may use different
mechanisms like State transitions or ke
learning three action selection in
active inference actions are selected to
minimize expected free energy G which
includes both the expected surprise and
uncertainty about future
States equation 2.6 in the 2022 textbook
other models actions are often selected
based on maximizing Rewards or following
predefined strategies cool nice free
energy calculations in active inference
where and how act where and how free
energy is calculated One agent
initialization that's the
ABCDE here's action sampling AC agents
sample actions based on their current
beliefs and the goal of minimizing
expected free energy free energy update
agent. update free energy agents update
their free energy based on the new
observation and actions taken and during
each time step the script tracks various
metrics including average expected free
energy a efe list and variational free
energy a vfe list why free energy is
important oh
wow perception and action free energy
unifies perception and action under a
single framework by minimizing free
energy agents improve their models of
the world and select actions that reduce
uncertainty and prediction error
adaptation this approach allows agents
to adapt to changing environments
dynamically as they continuously update
their beliefs and actions to minimize
free energy and some code Compares with
other models reinforcement learning
focuses on maximizing cumulative
reward rule-based models use predefined
rules evolutionary algorithms use
populationbased search methods which Nim
and I recently have explored in the in
the traveling salesperson problem and
the ant colony optimization so pretty
cool thanks Andrew for making the
original open-source educational
materials
let's go a little bit deeper into PDP
poll okay here we're in systems active
inference PDP poll it's a super fun
script I hope that PDP Learners
respector out there give it a try let's
open it in the integrated
terminal Python 3 PDP pull here's what
this does first it clones into the
specific repo of pmdp
then it lists all the
methods and it rolls through all the
methods in the subm modules and it
writes it to pmdp methods. markdown so
this is this a markdown file that is um
let's see 2 200 lines long but how cool
these are all the PDP methods listed
documentation really matters here's the
arguments for pmdp do aent which is in
the agent subm module so here we can see
the full arguments the aity of the agent
and example
usage this is not being generated by llm
this is just being pulled from the dock
strings and the information that's in
the PDP package so again those
contributions the questions that people
ask really do matter here's PDP
algorithms run MMP that's marginal
message passing for updating marginal
posterior beliefs it might be buried
somewhere who knows where in a script
and here it is brought out for all to
see in terms of the parameters that are
used and what it returns so it's like hm
wow this is really a cool way to study
and learn any package but here just in
the PDP setting like 1,000 lines
later pmdp do control. update posterior
policies full factorized here we see
okay we have a BC a factor all these
arguments what does it do and this is
the dock string not llm generated but
this is awesome for helping read what
the doc strings are not by scanning
through and seeing the plain text of the
code but rather by being able to look
and say like hm okay what were the
comments written but with
pmdp we could also pretend for a second
like we are going to use some llms for
development here we'll use command I
we'll say
update and professionalize these methods
without altering
function for example
with Comprehensive doc
strings we
missing Andrew in live chat wrote
amazing work Daniel thank you for
presenting my work and more importantly
expanding on the original goal open
source learning open source resources
totally okay so here we're going to
update and then we we'll put in like a a
a a special word or just kind of like a
weird
symbol but if we ran the
um PDP poll again it would pull the
whole pmdp cleanly so it won't include
our updates also
cursor doesn't at this time do very well
it says above 400
lines uh certainly it gives mixed
results once you get like over 500 or a
th000 lines it does give mixed results
for example sometimes it'll do a fix
like up near the top of the document
okay we're about to find
out it'll do a fix up at the top and
then it'll be like okay and then delete
the rest so here it's just showing this
is like llm augmented development
on PBP now this is funny because what it
did for the dock strings to the
underlying functions was it it peeped
into the summary we already had and now
it's re-entering the dock string in
terms of what it has for parameters and
returns so again not saying that's the
right way to update but this starts to
get into looking really cool like oh
maybe there could be like unified
formats for what the doc strings are and
we could use the active inference
ontology in a really coherent way and
have the inputs and outputs and the
arguments of each of the functions
that's important for translation
learning and for our accessibilities
also for machine sense making so pretty
cool I'm going to delete the PDP
repo version here and and
that's where we got to with PDP pole. py
and studying the PDP Library okay into
part three cognitive sovereignty
okay
so cognitive sovereignty and act of
inference in the state of exception this
was a paper that I wrote in October last
year and the paper provides an analysis
of Georgio agamben's book homo seer in
the tradition of active inference I'll
just read this first paragraph homoa
articulates the relationship between be
life and political existence in Western
politics and metaphysics a gambin argues
that politics is founded on the
inclusive exclusion of be life or
natural biological life the physiology
and cognition of the body but reading
later and more I understood it's not
simply only that is politicized only
through its exclusion as an exception
drawing on Aristotle's definition of as
a political animal a gambin traces the
historical development of this structure
and its continuation in modern
biopolitics so in this paper which was
super fun to write and I got helpful
feedback from colleagues as well first
reviewed my reading of homo SRE and some
of the logic of sovereignty Drew an
illusion between normal politics and the
state of exception to normal and
revolutionary science in the coonan
Paradigm then played off this kind of
fully syn thetic concept synthetic
intelligence to explore cognitive
sovereignty and then consider a
situation that we were modeling where
active inference agents are having a
normal political scenario then there's a
crisis which induces a state of
exception and then three terms from the
active inference ontology but this is
kind of a Mad Lib plug-and
playay affordances and how that changes
during the state of exception
variational free energy into terms of
bare life and expected free energy in
terms of the sovereign's agency during
the state of exception and then wrote an
active State forence model Sovereign
agency in the state of exception and
gave some pseudo code so it was a fun
paper to write reviewed some of this
Humanities and political sciences
scholarship and then got to some pseudo
code earlier llms o October 2023
and then okay what what what could we do
next well we could include a bunch of
other
topics and then we could also like
actually make functions we could we
could make the functions that are
described and we could go from active
State for the sketch above to active
govern ants for example multi-agent
setting cognitive security Quantum
cognitive sovereignty all these kinds of
fun topics so following a recipe a meta
recipe
that we've seen many many times first
what I did is I brought in the cognitive
sovereignty paper so I just copied in
the full
paper
280 lines because one line is like a
whole paragraph It's about the number of
tokens anyway but the new line thing
this is kind of a cool feature um then I
basically just did control a for all
contr K and then I prompted and said
okay write a
specification for what the model
actually is and so it it describes okay
well you describe the state space this
is kind of like chapter 6 from the 2022
textbooks what is the hierarchical
nature if any how do we think about
Precision on what variational free
energy expected free energy what is the
state of exception what is triggering
the state of exception how do we build a
generative model generative process what
algorithm do we need how do we think
about the multi-agent setting how do we
think about cognitive security and then
how do we think optionally about Quantum
exceptions and extensions scenario
generation
validation ethical considerations so
this is a technical
spec that provides a comprehensive
blueprint for implementing an active
inference generative model to study
cognitive sovereignty and states of
exception it incorporates key Concepts
from the original paper while providing
concrete implementation details and
extensions then I kind of asked it to go
one more step and said make a technical
prospectus for this project and again
this is a smaller but pretty similar so
that that those resources are there and
then just go to the gear and then
features re
resync I I don't know how often it
resyncs by itself but it's just good to
know okay we're all C
up close
Pap close
ter okay now let's open up the
script so
main.py is going to do some pretty cool
stuff and these are like meta patterns
that are just so useful there's a
config.js that has the parameters here
it's just the input and output
directories and then how many times
steps before the crisis are we going to
simulate and then how many time steps
after the crisis are we going to
simulate there's a utilities that
contains the different kinds of class
and function definitions and then main
is going to call in three steps also
printing each line of the output in real
time main is going to call one two 3 so
first it's going to run one generate an
entity Library we'll look at the
structure of that two it's going to run
the
simulation according to the config and
then three it's going to perform a
simulation analysis also based upon the
config but I don't think there's any
analysis free parameters but it could be
so Python 3 in the terminal
main.py running one so let's look at the
outputs to
terminal generating entity library for
cognitive sovereignty simulation it say
gives an entity library. Json to the
output folder we'll look at through
these there's 15 entities there's five
kinds of entities we got government
corporation NOS media and citizen groups
and then we have entity 123 for each
type it starts out where government one
is in power all the others are not in
power okay now it's running the
simulation the simulation actually runs
like super fast but it takes a few
seconds to plot one of the figures let's
just look at the entity Library while
it's
running okay so here's how each entity
is
described
um these
are well spaced
matrices that describe the transitions
amongst five different
states um the five different
states are
in power so that's when you start or
when you gain power then there's three
kind of continuously varying States this
is just a five State discrete model high
medium and low power so this is kind of
like close to being in power medium
power and then low power and then
there's homo secre which is the category
for that which can be killed with
impunity explored in the book of the
same name so here we
go let's look back to the terminal then
we'll look over all the other outputs
okay ran the simulation visualize this
is the step that takes the longest just
by visualization methods but it's a big
figure um entity traces are recorded
then the simulation analysis is wrong so
okay let's look at the analysis plain
teex summary but it'll get more colorful
so we see okay State volatility these
are just volatility levels like
government one has the lowest variance
through time probably because for the
first 200 time steps it just stayed in
power whereas the other ones were
bouncing around during phase
one here uh most common States so let's
see here's the most common States before
and after the crisis like Corporation 1
was most commonly in low power but then
afterwards it was most commonly in the
Homer state or so on and then this top
part State percentages so here's
Corporation 2 here's it before it was
bouncing between high medium and low
power these are just random matricies so
it's not super surprising that they're
roughly being uh drawn but but here we
see like citizen group one was spending
more of its time in a low power
situation but then after the crisis it
was spending you know 18% of the time in
the high power 39 in the homo okay
here's the traces of the visualization
so it's a little bit condensed we could
run one for like 10 time steps if you
want to see the bouncing around oh but
very
interestingly this could be a slightly
different one actually that line up so
that was the government one got
displaced in the crisis some new group
maybe that's media 2 but it just happens
to be a very similar color but it is a
different one that comes
in here's the results of the simulation
many many thousands of
lines here we see the the overall
occupancy of the different states so we
had one out of 15 were in power before
and one out of 15 stayed in power after
as different one and then here's like
the introduction in this kind of um toy
situation there was no homre before the
crisis but then it opened up like this
Niche um State percentages the
visualizations are a little bit fun they
have their own charm to them but here we
see like government one was spending
100% of its time before in power and
then after it has but these are
overlapping bar charts that could be
just visually
clarified um but we can see like which
one was most like media 2 was spending
100% of the power after okay this is the
big figure so each row is an
entity and then let's look at these B
matrices so here all
start out at Baseline and government one
is just given the power initially but at
Baseline you stay in homre if you're
already there but no one starts there so
no one is there
initially and you stay in power if
you're already there again same thing
one is just given it so the others that
aren't in power are just bouncing around
in this submatrix between high medium
and low so these are transition matrices
just Markov chain
processes then once the crisis happens
there's two kinds of States there's
empowered and disempowered so for all
entities once you're empowered like
there's no secondary changes in power
structure in this simulation once you're
Empower you stay there when you're
empowered you just stay in power when
you're disempowered now you can this is
from to two once you're disempowered so
that means like you're not the sovereign
after the state of exception has
begun
from to so here if you are if if you
happen to just for that first time step
be in power then you get kicked to high
power with one that's what they all have
that one there and then now you're
exploring this four
submatrix amongst high medium low and
Homo Seer
so kind of cool um gives a starting
point and and um we could possibly fuse
that with pmdp because in the paper the
definition of sovereignty cognitive
sovereignty was for one's own e to
influence the vfe of others so when the
political operativi of One agent
influence the bare life of another
that's a state of exception that's
political agency so that was the
cognitive sovereignty simulation it's
like
cursor and the
llm probably could have gotten there a
year ago a little bit less than a year
ago so it's like not that this
simulation was implausible it's just
accelerating more and more with going
from even the pseudo Cod I don't know
how how much it was
needed because it was itself just sort
of giving a few
sketches so cool
okay we'll possibly return and add PDP
like meanwhile if anyone in the live
chat has a request or a
thought um otherwise we'll look at this
fourth section and then we'll
recap look at all these suggestions it's
like did you mean eternal return is that
what you
meant okay fo you let's let's bring in a
kind of realist twist so in other
there's all these different Frameworks
and uh different kinds of systems hence
systems within systems and let's go to
Foya all
right United States Freedom of
Information Act Foya this was generated
material is a pivotal federal statute
enacted 1966 designed to ensure
transparency and accountability in
government operations by granting public
access to Federal agency records key
technical details included
it's an actimate and purpose scope
request process exemptions appeals and
litigation
fees electronic Foya there was a 1996
eoa Amendment mandating the electronic
availability of certain records in the
establishment of electronic reading
rooms whoa and annual reports Foya is an
essential mechanism for fostering
government transparency and
accountability enabling the public to
remain informed about governmental
actions and decisions okay so there's a
few different scripts in here there's a
main.py this is just a wrapper that's
going to call several of these other
scripts but let's look through them so
foil
utils first it loads an API key from the
EnV file so as brought up before in the
context of llm apis get ignore is at the
top level of the repo and here you can
specify types of files like file
extensions and also whole subfolders
like when we clone in other big repos we
don't need to then push those as if they
were kind of ours that kind of breaks
the git chain but we see EnV here so
what happens in utils is it's going to
load
in using the EnV python package the API
key fora API key so each person is going
to get in their API key and mine is in
here I'm not going to show it on the
Stream but then when you make your API
request it will use your API key and
then you can keep your EnV with your
secret keys for llms or for the
government or whatever it is and you
know that it's not going to get pushed
to GitHub like when you do a push um
utils has different
utilities here are some example Foya
calls that are just like more form
formulaic
there's an analysis and a markdown
translator and then agency
year has a start and an end year so here
we did 2000 to
2025 but I also explored doing like
1,200 to
2400 just thousands of years that we
wouldn't expect but we never know and
then also about a few days ago when I
initially did this I got rate limited so
I had to have some email correspondences
to restore my access but that itself was
fun and
interesting then I used llm I just would
copy this let's just
see shift here just selecting this
control K just to bring in just that
part add any missing
agencies okay let's just see if and I
just did that several times just to to
get a bunch of agencies
I I don't even know these may not even
be real let's see if any are added
here okay more
agencies it's like okay now now you've
gone too far let's just see really
quick USDA aphis this sounds
agricultural yeah animal and plant
health inspection service that's real
kind of like aphid some of these it's
like really though
see that J mmfl doesn't seem to be an
actual one but regardless that's just
going to um still get called so again it
takes the start and end year and all the
Departments listed we could we could um
do a hashtag out or we could change the
all agencies we could say list of just
and then just delete that if we only
wanted major apartments or of course you
could just delete the ones you don't
want and then just say okay only
interested in NSF for this year okay um
it it sorts it
alphabetically converts it to dictionary
and then it fetches this utility if if
we were you know but this is a common
move so so I I might as well just show
it select all and then did I but it is
it it wasn't really needed because even
just pulling up I control I with the
composer it already brought in this
script then I'm just going to again just
for for for doubling
check add into the context window fo
utils move all the methods defined in at
foore agency year to
foore
utils and invoke
them properly
here so expected Behavior would be it's
going to delete red lines are going to
show up from 93 to 108 and then we'll be
able to check and again this is why
being able to here it is it's drafting
on these two
subtabs and then let's see how it goes
so whoa so but it can go too far
so it it it may for I'm not going to
accept this edit this time just because
I know is already working this looks
like it might have gone too far but if
it's a
um what what it usually does or what you
can get it to prompt to do is just pull
methods that are
defined with defa pull them into utils
like what it would manually look like
would be copying in contrl X cutting out
defa putting that to Foya
utils and then ensuring
that the um Foya agency Year from Foy
utils is pulling in Fetch and save
annual reports so it'll still work okay
so what what is this
output clear the terminal we're still in
cognitive sovereignty I'm just just
going to trash that
terminal right
click open an integrated
terminal Python
3 let's just do
main okay so main we did an update but
again this is what it looks like to to
debug just put it into the
composer fix it meanwhile let's call the
the fo agency here
accept it again looking is probably a
good thing to do it's like it's not just
like not looking before crossing the
street it's like not looking when making
stochastic edits to your PhD
dissertation which is Live code but
s okay there we go so even without
intervention fo agency year Okay so what
it's doing is it maybe we're getting
rate limited I'm not sure um for each of
those departments it's
saving these outputs so we'll keep
watching what's happening live I'm not
sure maybe this is going to be about to
be a huge one but first it checks if we
already have that exact combination of
agency and year then I concatenate in
the file name this is just one way to do
it it could be done like way better ways
um the date that it was pulled that's
um I'm not sure if that last piece the
time but then the middle piece here is
like 19 characters because for this one
like 2,000 DOI let's just look at a
let's look at a
um let's look at the
USDA okay so 2005 it's 19 characters
long you're going to see a lot of 19s
because 19 just says report not found so
if you request what what was the annual
report for the USDA in like the year
3400 probably it's not found on that
server not saying it's not there but
then we can see okay here's 2010 annual
report okay interesting but we got
it so this is their
Foya
metadata as far as I totally understand
this is all open information I am not
doing anything other than just calling
the Foya
API so we can see how many characters
are there and then it's like 2024 and
2025 are back to 19 characters because
those reports are not
there um not not sure like it'll be
interesting to see what what comes out
here okay but I'm just going to kill it
clear and then let's
call Foya to mark down so here it's
going to make a Foya markdown folder so
it's just iterating over all the reports
it's giving a lot of Errors maybe we
could debug it but we'll see let's go to
doe so here's the 19 character one
report not found but here's the 43 okay
now this is looking a little bit more
readable let's make a new script called
Foya secondary MD
processing.
py it's already in the context window
I'll add into the
window a
markdown that we know has a lot of
characters so we'll do doe 2008
let let's try without specific reference
to a file it would work with reference
to a specific file but just make sure
that it doesn't overfit there let's say
given markdown
documents in do slash that means this
folder
Foya underscore markdown
slash folder and all sub
folders right
secondary processing
algorithm
that reads
in and
improves formatting and
conciseness
saving all outputs to a folder Dot
slash Foya secondary markdowns slash
open parentheses make it if it is not
there
recapitulating Boulder nested
topology thank you I'm curious to see
because it's not going to do an llm call
but if you'll recall back to INF for ant
stream one
and the kinds of llm API augmentations
that were
possible then we could imagine okay now
inray over all these reports and do llm
summary or do translation or explain it
to this person okay let's just see how
it
goes all
right clear we're in the Foya
folder here's secondary MD processing
Python 3 Foya tab it goes to the point
where it's ambiguous and then secondary
MD processing okay no module
bs4 some people might know ways to fix
this but let's just see what it
recommends okay it adds some I'll just
accept it
clear run it
again error beautiful soup for not
installed installing it now so this is
what's so fun and collaborative is like
oh hm okay I came across that friction
and then just within a few seconds okay
but now no one else will hit that exact
friction okay interesting let's look at
what it's
doing
whoa okay this is processing from ones
that are that are like just kind of
empty in so we'll see what those maybe
those have a different
format but it it'll get through them
okay it just looks like it's spacing it
out but you
know what's wrong with
that and then let's see when it goes
through the subfolders or what happens
then okay it's almost done with the ones
that were just in the folder itself
meanwhile um this is like the last
section that I had prepared to go
through so please write any comments or
questions or ideas in the live chat and
then we can play around a little bit and
and do a little more
developments okay here we go
OIP
okay
okay okay not okay OIP might be an
exception okay let's see another one
HUD okay so 19 okay this is the report
not found and here's
okay
okay you
know is this helpful possibly would uh
llm being used in this Loop be helpful
yeah
probably okay um just pull this off
screen for a Split Second
but api.
data.gov I mean this is what
USA OS
is like when we think
about what what what is USA OS
well interestingly I'm getting some very
strange internet patterns from the other
window which I'm not going to show but
let's just end that one and see if I can
pull up
Usos
wow very
interesting here I've just navigated
over here but here's from my person
page drawing from Kirby earner Usos but
it's like has it ever been
more API
oriented to interface with speak program
utilize the USA operating
system not
sure okay clear
it close the terminal I'm going to
delete the um
markdowns because those can be
regenerated but I'll leave the responses
that already came in just because those
are information it just kind of like a
it's an API call that anyone could have
made I'm just listing them there so that
was the
foyer
okay all
right all
right
okay let Let's uh recap there was a
couple sections here going from the end
to the
first most recently we looked at this
Freedom of Information Act API call
scraping processing handling pathway and
and explored with the git ignore how you
can put your own personal API key into
EnV you need an email address to sign up
and then that's a way where like many
people can collaborate on the open
source tooling while also keeping their
API
secret that's the Foya then we looked at
in in folder nine under other and then
we looked at two different um well I
guess
three folders within zero context
systems now here going in in forward
chronological order we looked at William
Blake's work entity extraction some
processing and some Snippets from Blake
for for augmented Blake frints
looked at cognitive sovereignty skipping
to the third one of the first
three talked about how this meta recipe
for bringing in a resource folder asking
it to write a technical spec or a
perspectus and then writing
software that's very well structured and
articulated for further development with
utilities and Mains and configs and and
how that resulted in some pretty
interesting outputs like just about
looking about TR transition matrices and
setting us up to integrate with pmdp
which which we very well could do if
someone mentions it in the live chat in
the coming
minutes and then lastly in the active
inference system section the pmdp pull
method and I'll leave the P methods
up let's
just intra
stream3 push it and then let's read pmdp
method in in its natural
context that was 1 hour ago reload the
page reload the
page now it says now zero
context systems active inference PDP
methods this is like getting into oh wow
this is like kind of nicely formatted
this is like something you could take on
a nice
trip
okay Andrew P is writing a few things in
the chat I'll
I'll wait a few seconds while you type
out some more ideas anyone else though
again please write any ideas and for a a
couple of minutes here let's just chill
see see what else we can explore and
learn and
do actually actually while while people
are writing I'm just going to do a quick
overview on on what is in these
different folders so starting in zero
computer languages this is a a language
name brain this is a brain
implementation of active
inference famously an obscure
Arcane bizarre coding language but why
not right it's all just
semantics then we have brain active
inference goang thing agent definition
Java active INF forance Pearl Julia in
Julia it's not done yet but kobis e has
done incredible work on visualization
and many many other things and so I was
working to get a script working that
would render the kinds of images that
he's doing and do a bunch of other stuff
but that's just in progress rust and
then like hilarious stuff like active
shelfer I mean this is a shell script
that does active inference this is
really highlight the semantics and the
syntax and the space between and and the
kinds of poll jumping that we can do
back and forth specs and prompts some
early documents meta
informats um bio informat systems folder
we have active inference C of
sovereignty ic2 S2 and William Blake we
went into today p3f and some of the
bolts business legal operating technical
social these were explored in some other
streams about legal engineering and the
three RS and all that so that's the zero
context folder that's setting
context here's in prepare this is a fun
folder it has a ton of it has
config with all these configurations for
an ant active inference multi-agent
simulation then there's meta config that
configs the config and then there's Meta
Meta config that configures the meta
config we have cognitive security
cryptography digital twin design
processing digital twin
metaphysics metaphysics spec generator
this is the speculative realism coding
at play nested systems systems within
systems invoking the category Theory
networking phermones the fairmon
ontology Quantum ferone environment and
then a little bit of culinary delight
with the salt fat acid heat
PDP methods this is where there's a
variety of methods that are developed
with llms and research methods learning
education also please contribute to
everything and then things here's
different things including a generic
generic generic generic logged
constructed
thing so context again is just sort of
like a bunch of different things that
contextualize for us and for Shirley
cursor one is preparing with configs and
the things definition and the methods
definition then two goes into operate
here is
planning rendering a plan executing the
rendered plan of a simulation and having
situational Anta awareness along the
way that's the actual operativity of the
simulation then we have measurements
measuring the
simulation four reporting on the
measurement of the simulation
five following up and specifying and
executing the followup on the reporting
of the
simulation six is an API for meta and
format for knowledge I don't have too
much in here seven and eight are not
there and then nine is this meta pattern
where we clone in the GitHub repos or
the GitHub users for a given domain like
the brain these the brain API and then
bring them in reindex cursor then
program and then we can delete the
original repos so that that's a fun way
for if there's like something that
people want to integrate there's a few
multi-agent llm techniques and like AGI
related things that would be pretty
interesting maybe for a feature
one so that's the active infan package
okay thank you Andrew I'm going to copy
what you wrote
in okay let's go back to zero
systems
3.1 okay let's just do 3.2 MD as if
there was the do two okay Andrew wrote
quick thought on active pmdp cursor AI
integration flow one build out work
scripts plus add to repo EG example
social sciences two cursor reads working
script repo to Aid in building
recreating new simulation use cursor's
help as much as possible to finish the
simulation do manually what it can
cannot it's
Horizon three rinse and repeat we hit
the limits of the currently existing llm
llms along the way but we build the repo
and available acadm simulations
resources as we go while improving the
repo's ability to provide cursor with
useful information for improving next
script building iteration I believe this
is what you're proposing just exercising
my own understanding of it here smiley
face okay thank you Andrew I'm going
delete that last one now let us do this
contrl a contrl
k operationalize this into a
comprehensive development plan for what
I
will immediately do after after your
response comma
llm I don't know if it's been explored
whether they're saying things like thank
you or speaking to it a certain way
help awesome
okay okay
okay make a new folder called um
augmented active inference
okay let's just try this here we're in
3.2 MD so we just took a few super chats
from Andrew and and spec it out okay so
create a new GitHub repo doesn't need to
be a GitHub
repo build working
scripts cursor AI integration
documentation and testing iteration
Improvement next steps continuous
integration okay control I uh contr a
control I wasn't necessary it's just
bring it's like the whole file and lines
1 through 62 but that's the whole thing
but it's
just it's a habit what can I
say do all of this making all the files
needed saving the new files as created
in do slash augmented active infant okay
let's see
certainly okay it it looks like it's
doing that in the top level repo of the
[Music]
um whole INF for ants but we'll we'll
bring this in and we'll just replace the
this folder that we made
okay Dragon here we
go
okay re re reset
reset this is just because I I I rug
pulled where it had written it and and
moved it
okay here we go okay script
overview social science sim. py
implements a basic social science
simulation using
PDP
okay save it close it social science
okay from pmdp import agent inference
learning social agents
okay I'm going to run pmdp
poll just so that we have the actual
pmdp repo actually let let's see if we
don't need that
first
okay we're in the
augmented okay social agent run
simulation
okay utils.py
process visualize calculate tests cool
unit
testing all
right open it with integrated terminal
so we're all the way deep we're we're
deep into this cursor augmented
situation Python
3 social science Sim okay nothing
happened here control I add extensive
logging here and in the
whole just here so we can have
better understanding and achieve in this
folder the aims of 3.2
okay certainly I'll enhance the logging
in the social science sim. py script to
provide a more comprehensive
oh okay okay look
good
now add the utils into the
context probably not necessary probably
not necessary but
move all
methods to at
utils.py
and invoke them here that's what I was
trying to do earlier so let's just see
what it does now
so it deleted these definitional
statements and then we see it added them
into
utils save it close the
utils so read me for this repo all right
let's let's just quickly let's just push
it augmentation
push then let's read the read me in its
not natural
habitat okay augmented active
inference read
me oh
interesting okay it was empty because it
wasn't saved in its place reload the
page here it is okay active cursor
integration integration of active
inference principles with cursor AI for
social science
simulations
okay
no clear it up we're in social science
Sim make all needed improvements to
achieve the aims of read me
move all
method definitions to at utils.py
and invoke them
here let see it's doing this this is a I
I I believe this will be fixed in the
future version but sometimes it'll be
like going all the way back up the repo
there there might be a way to to to do
this just better with how the paths are
handled let's just see what happens when
we run it first
okay cannot import name agent from
pmdp fix this but we know that it has
access to PDP methods. markdown so this
is the one that's like the study guide
for what PDP does now for a human
human reading this document as mentioned
earlier it's probably great for trains
long car rides you know dark room rooms
all these kinds of places where you
might want to read something just really
pay attention to it but it's the perfect
high density semantics that will be
helpful here let's just accept whatever
it did see if it did better and then if
not we'll give it a little help no
module name p dp. aent it's a new
error fix this so let's just keep on
finding and quashing some bugs and let's
just see if like can we get to a PDP
with we haven't brought in the pmdp repo
but it will work if we pull if we clone
in the repo then we can explicitly
invoke the
functions P DP has no attribute agent
okay so we we we could be going around
circles or
not I apologize for the confusion it's
like no no I wasn't confused you don't
need to
apologize I think that this this
composer functionality again super cool
and there's also probably ways to use it
a lot better because it has a
whole another view
layover that that I'm I'm not really
even exploring at this
time okay can not import util so
we're so when when it's one kind of line
of flight and just like quashing bugs
that seem to be of a similar ilk I'll
keep it rolling in the same
composer but then when it's a different
Vector we're going to do a pivot then we
can do a new one okay no module PP
distributions so it's kind of fixing a
series of Errors related to ACC
accurately calling PDP subm
modules this could be like super pmdp
file structure
specific but nonetheless that's where we
are okay okay okay this version
implements a simplified version of
simple agent using only
numpy we've replaced the pmtp specific
operations with basic numpy let's see
what it looks like
wow like so then it's like then then who
was
semantics if it takes the
PDP PDP
semantics you
know was it all
what
okay okay
okay got some plotting mat lib plot
errors but I could see from the top okay
that it that it was doing stuff so in
social science sim.
py um save all terminal logs to a file
log.txt
save all
output files SLV
visualizations to a
folder in this
folder output
slash make the
folder if not
there Claude 3.5
Sonic doing it
today okay accept it save it clear it
clear a terminal double up run
it okay got an unexpected
argument fix
it here we go we have agent one and
Agent
Zero receiving observations updating
beliefs taking
actions
amazing see here it just put that over
here so let's look at this one this is
in the correct location
this one
is 100 lines long this one is like it's
seven lines long just Implement that one
little stub but then it did it in the
wrong place I I don't know if that's I'm
just using it weirdly or if if it's just
getting confused because we're really
deep in this nested repo if you just do
kind of like one project per repo like
William Blake repo cognitive sovereignty
repo then the embedding IS F faster
there's less context but that's kind of
the Delight also is all all this mixed
interactive
semantics okay clear run it again we're
going to get the probably same error oh
well but where did it save the logs
to ensure all terminal outputs are saved
in this folder to log.txt
then we'll move all the
methods also just for for context here's
the system prompt that I give cursor use
professional functional modular concise
elegant interpretable python use
comprehensive logging to terminal and
all other programming best practices I'm
going to delete that part because maybe
it's not it's overlearning on that
accept save it clear it clear it run
it okay now we got to this this eror
again fix
this okay we'll we'll we'll progress a
little bit further on this bring in a
few pmdp methods till then though if
anyone wants to
uh see it went again now it's editing
social science Sim Utilities in the
outer
folder so it's
like
why but if anyone writes a live chat
with like a thought or a question we can
definitely do
it
okay also again we know that we'd be
able to bring in the full clone in pmdp
and then just explicitly reference it
and that's like that's not even a bad
strategy but let's see if we can do it
without cloning in the
repo
so move all methods to
at fills.
py and
invoke properly
here
okay
okay accept it save it I'm going to copy
in just another message that Andrew
wrote and read it
here uh FYI with appreciation to the
work being done by both the SPM and Pi
Pi DMP mdp which is heavily based on SPM
I can confirm via hours of repo cross
referencing there's no easy route from
either of these you can't get there from
here packages and their dependencies to
an easy ready too simulation Builder
already simulating two agents even
before inscript inspecting the script
logic awesome big feet thank you awesome
Andrew cool okay but another way we
could do this would
be oh simulation
results okay there's three agents
they're taking actions over
time just by calling
this okay now let's see what happens
let's just reindex cursor make sure that
we're in the right spot
so here it's it's all all the files that
we touched it's it needs to reindex it
might do a little mini re indexing when
you call something into local context
but but I don't know
okay bring it into the
composer
Now update this update and extend these
methods invoking where possible at pmdp
methods so that's the one that we've
been looking at and enjoying which is
it's like the doc strings and the input
output for all these pmdp
functions
okay let's see how it
does it's it it drafts it up here so
here's like where the generation is
happening and then then once it finishes
this V1
draft
then it runs
through
okay and it goes through again second
pass it's kind of like measure twice cut
once
situation okay save it clear a
composer social agents here we see ABC
it's like Q qpi is actually doing the
EXP Ed free energy based model updating
for A and
B okay now over
here
comprehensively develop I'm using the
control K version here just for a little
little
flavor um using the at utils.py
to achieve the mission of double
3.2 maybe there's a way to do in the
system prompt like just
say um and this is also where like
programming practice and expertise and
all this comes into play like
maybe maybe there's a way to make sure
like that we always always call The Run
script Main and then we always call the
utils like utils underscore and then the
type of
utils then we could have a system prompt
that's like I only like to run scripts
called main myself and please ensure
that utils uncore asterisk are
comprehensive and you know make it so
that Carl friston would smile upon it
clear social science Sim okay can't Port
name control new errors fix
it script overview meanwhile while the
control I is going control K develop
this given all we know
now except whatever it
says clear run it again reset that one's
done accept it pop back to social
science Sim can't import inference new
one fix it meanwhile back to
3.2 develop this given what we know
now okay see here now utils again is
going to the wrong
place we'll get it
there let's just see what it does
okay
okay okay oh create contribution guid
lines for potential collaborator set up
a project Wiki for detailed
documentation tutorial consider
presenting the project at relevant
conferences or meetups like the fourth
applied active inference Symposium from
November 13th to 15th 2024 possibly
let's just
say
develop section
n comprehensively
comma absurdly comma professionally
then we'll pop back to the simulator
okay okay okay okay all right it's all
about nine
now wow okay talk about cart before the
horse it's
like why why not just focus on Section n
aren't you interested in like
subsections reject it it's okay we know
it would
okay
okay okay Andrew wrote typically in fer
Paul season sample action functions are
called separately albeit often
adjacently as PP the llm seem to realize
it could combine them into a single
function flow okay let say now given at
so and then Andre wrot subject to change
of course point is fascinating to see
how the llm might make optimizations not
inherent to the original libraries I
mean yes that's that's very
characteristically understated yes it it
suggests stuff that's like it's an
adjacency in like Dimension
754 but for a given person it's like it
might pop up to your awareness in a
moment it might not but even if what
popped up in your aw Wess were like
awesome Epic professional modular absurd
great every single second or you're
doing it 10 times a second it's like you
still might never just riff enough let
alone capture and do that kind of cosmic
fishing um explain this comprehensively
okay so now wall contr L is
going reset it let's add in the utils
run it but we know it's going to give an
error add it to the
composer fix this with reference SL
modification only to the local
folder
okay combining invert policy sample
action functions to a single function or
flow can streamline the simulation
process
clear it run
it no module pmdp alos fix
this it's making a lot of changes so
it's like again there's there's so many
ways to do the professional
programming this is just one sort of
pythonic
strategy okay now it's bringing in p
mdp these
units save
it clear it double up run can't import
name
inference fix
it also it's like we could have just add
in oh it's it can't import inference
maybe inference doesn't even exist
that's that's those are a few of the
situations see now it might just be kind
of floundering right here let's
see no module pdp.com
DP and just see what they are but but
this also relate this is getting like
pretty specific into
pdp's folder and subm module
structure yeah yeah just maybe uh 10 to
30 more minutes but if people have
comments or questions please just go for
it okay so there it's just saying you
know what ignore that core
mention run
it okay cannot import inference delete
it cannot import control
we let's just accept importing pmdp
period fix
this
however yeah okay Andrew wrote inference
alos Etc do exist but the dependency
structure is highly complex
yeah okay I I
okay okay okay let's let's do a little
let's do some radical pmdp
surgery here okay CD double dot pop up a
level LS that's what's there CD double
dot pop up a level LS there's better
ways to do this I'm just showing one way
to do it CD active inference now we're
in active inference not the augmented
one okay
reload our llms get them ready
okay Python
3 PDP pull clone in
pmdp
okay okay here we
go new script this is going to be called
Flat
pmdp uncore
flatten py
okay
here given all the
functions in pmdp
package iterate over the entire python
package
oh write a script that will it over the
entire entire python package pulling out
all python method slash
entity
definitions EG across and through
modules sub folders
Etc
and output a mega I won't use that
output a Tex text
file pmdp methods
flat.
py which let's do PDP
utils oh PDP
all
utils which contains
verbatim all
pmdp methods for the calling
okay so we're going to generate the the
script here that's going to flatten
pmdp okay it again it it pulled it up
here copy it P to be flatten paste it
in
okay okay
like if if this works on one
shot okay there's PDP flatten Python 3
pmdp uncore
flatten okay what do you think extract
definitions as walk process package
main all right
okay
okay it little bit of weirdness just
because of
um IO operations on closed file
that could be just due to like something
weird about how I opened
the
okay extracted 24
definitions all
right all right
looking
good ensure that
this script iterates through all
folders and sub folders within do SL
pmdp
now
it let's just see OS
walk accept it save it clear it double
up run it 24
definitions still I am only getting 24
definitions there should be
hundreds no this e even if we get to
hundreds it won't be the right output
right because like there's going to be a
method defined in utils and I expect
there'll be a similar one in slj SL
utils
okay clear double up run
it okay
okay look in this very folder comma my
colleague there are
subfolders in what was cloned
by P DP
pull that output there is the whole pmdp
script that's what we need the whole
team to look through so we can get all
hundreds of
methods to make a
flattened single Mega utils file for
simpler
referencing remember we're just
nmes the script is looking at the
installed PDP package instead of locally
cloned
repo there we
go but why didn't you just say
so now there we
go
456 to all
utils okay now I'm going to pull this
back
into the
scripts well done cursor take a quick
breather okay clear CD double dot pull
up CD augmented enter
LS CD scripts
LS go over to cursor double check it's
all reindexed delete the original PDP
there it is new
files we'll just make sure it gets them
all
400 456 definitions says Andrew
incroyable that's like exactly how I
feel it's like what what OAB just
incroyable
day okay social science
Sim add in this context window pmvp all
utils develop this
multi-agent social
simulation given all methods fully
defined in
pmdp Corall utils.py in this
folder okay meanwhile well let's let
let's Let It edit then then
we'll okay
okay it's kind of writing it in the
composer
window again this is this might just be
a tiny cursor bug it'll be like there it
is there's my answer but it's like well
no let's or so it doesn't suggest a code
edit so I say suggest all those code
edits
to
social science Sim it's like oh I'm
sorry
yep pretty
cool okay now this is where it's doing
the composer mode correctly it opens up
a second tab then it writes all those
code edits there
and then it'll rescan this one and say
well this was my updated draft and this
was the original
draft so now pulls
in let's see how this
does fix
this remove the need to ask about
version if that is
simpler
okay utils.py
it's cuz it's calling
both the utils
and well let's just rename this one
utils
yeah rename this
utils well first let's just delete the
ones that we had we'll do we'll if we
call it utils old it might get confused
okay utils.py then social science Sim
utils
import
Star okay fix this removing the need for
the
method or invoking it or writing it if
it is
missing but then here here's the deal
utils.py which is the flattened all it's
it's 20,000 lines long so then it'll
have a hard time reaching in and making
the targeted edit to Something in
here see it's it might just be like oh
we don't need that
one let's see it might just be like
let's delete 19.9 out of the 20,000
lines
okay a file too long see edit command is
limited to files at most around 400
lines
long so then it just cancels it so I I I
I I get that I get
that all imdp
utils social science Sim
from all
PDP
utils save
it write this so that it only uses
functions defined in at all
pmdp
dets it Imports everything which is
perfect
perfect don't change
that use the
pmdp methods to make this multi-agent
simulation that
initializes
simulates and
visualizes a social multi-agent setting
we'll do a few more minutes if anyone
has like comments or questions let's see
them also again it's defining methods
here
so let see what it does
social agent now uses agent from pmdp
along with random a b
Etc
okay
okay remove the need for unit
test not sure what that is we can like
look
that's the unit testing
methods I
understand see but like do you like
philosophically do
you let's just ask it not that what it
says will be an answer philosophically
would you say that you fully
understand this
script and all it
implies it's kind of a trick question
because it's like all it
implies
okay accept it clear it double run
it okay let's try it here's what it
says did you mean okay yes I did mean
Python
3 okay so okay well there's the answer
for whether it thinks it understands it
but that's like that's like something
for people to
consider like this is why I leave the
same composer window running really make
sure
that social science Sim does not need
any unit test stuff at all
okay but
meanwhile new side chat just
dropped write a
hilarious age
appropriate esoteric lore
Laden who's on
first style dialogue
for fully
explaining
allegorically to someone familiar with
reinforcement
learning
everything happening in
this active
inference
multi- agent simulation
andure many baseball history
historical references comma as well
okay update this so that it runs with
just Python 3 social science sim. py no
commandline arguments
I think I accidentally terminated the
uh let's do Sonet I think it does
sometimes funnier who's on first
dialogue okay we have two two sonets
working for us
here got the the baseball dialogue slow
position 12 okay okay added the command
line arguments now we can call it the
way we
want accept it save
it reset it clear it double up run
it what did I say son it
ensure that unit test is not required at
all I
never this is something I've never said
before I never want to see that bug
again meanwhile
who's on first
MD okay
okay
okay oh let's not get ahead of
oursel save it clear it double
up fix it and remember what I said last
time we'll see if we can do like couple
more see if we fix it and then otherwise
we'll close with um reading the who's on
first summary and then at the end of
that I will read any comments that
people have or questions that they have
asked in the meanwhile and that will
conclude INF for an stream 3
no no you don't have to apologize I just
said remember what I
said all let's just see if cursor has
self-awareness fix this in a way where
you cursor don't give me that error
okay let's see how that goes okay
control shift L Andrew wrote
restructuring a library that's taken
years of development in various
programmers to develop not to mention
everything contributed to its SPN
precursor can it be done in a few
settings and I'll say that's what my oh
see file to
long to avoid cursor I'll make a more so
we we'll leave it there um we'll we'll
we'll push the
update so
updates not all fully
working the S Antics are basically there
though for any and all to build upon and
help
through okay we'll push that
structure this for professional markdown
viewing that's what my friend Andrew
said prepare a total response to him
that is respectful and age
appropriate okay
we're going to read the response to
Andrew then we're going to
push
Andrew I appreciate your perspective on
this you're absolutely right that
restructuring a library with years of
development history and contributions
for multiple programmers is significant
undertaking it's not something to be
taken lightly or rush
through dot dot dot dot dot dot dot dot
dot what are your thoughts this is kind
of like hold on there partner slow down
restructure pmdp by flattening it and
squeezing
it okay close it save it close
it we did what we
did save it close
it clear it close the terminal clear it
again close it goodbye cursor for a
day who is on first question mark
interobang then we'll read it there and
then I'll look at any live
chats augmented
docks okay here we
go it it always does the 27 Yankees okay
hey Costello have you heard about this
new active inference multi-agent
simulation it's like the 1927 Yankees of
AI the 1927 Yankees you mean with Babe
Ruth and L garig no no no I'm talking
about social agent and its teammates
they're like the murderer's row of
artificial intelligence wait who's on
first in this simulation no who's not in
this simulation we got social agent on
first observation at second and action
on third okay so who's social agent
exactly social agents on first just like
our old pal who I'm asking you who's
social agent no no social agent is like
Babe Ruth he's the heavy hitter of the
simulation he's got a random a matrix
and B Matrix just like the Bambino had
his legendary bat and
glove so social agent has a bat and
glove no he's got beliefs and policies
the a matrix is his belief about how
observations relate to Hidden States
like how the babe could read a picture
the B Matrix is his belief about how
actions change the world like how Ruth
knew just where to swing to hit it out
of the park all right what about about
second base you said observations there
that's right observation is like Earl
combes the Yankee center fielder always
watching Always observing in the
simulation observation feeds information
to social agent just like coms fed balls
to his teammates and actions on third
you've got it action is like Tony lazeri
the Yanke clutch hitter when social
agent needs to make a move action steps
up to the plate so
how do they play together well it's like
a perfectly executed Double Play No
Triple Play social agent uses his A and
B matrices to infer the best action just
like Ruth sizing up a pitch then action
takes that inference and makes a move
like lazeri turning a double play
meanwhile observation is constantly
updating the game State like Combs
tracking fly balls in the
Outfield but what's the goal of this
game huh that's where it gets
interesting the goal is to maximize
expected free energy which is like
trying to win the World Series of
cognition it's all about minimizing
surprise and uncertainty just like how
the 27 Yankees minimize their opponent's
chances of winning so they're trying to
predict what's going to happen exactly
it's like they're playing
interdimensional chess while everyone
else is playing checkers they're not
just reacting to the environment they're
actively trying to shape it just like
how Babe Ruth called his
shots this is making my head spin more
than a Dizzy Dean curveball okay that's
hilarious don't worry Castello just
remember in this game every agent is
trying to be the Babe Ruth of their own
cognitive World Series they're not just
learning from rewards like in Old School
reinforcement learning they're actively
inferring the best way to play the game
of
life I think I need to go sit in the
bullpen and think about this for a while
that's the spirit just like how active
inference agents are always updating
their models you're updating your
understanding you'll be a cognitive Hall
of Famer in no
time conclusion this allegorical
explanation aims to provide an intuitive
understanding of the active inference
multi-agent simulation by drawing
parallels with baseball Concepts and the
legendary 1927 New York Yankees team it
highlights key components such as the
social agent observation action as well
as Core Concepts like belief updating
and free energy
minimization all
right thanks everyone for watching that
was uh super fun hopefully you enjoyed
some of these methods and
demonstrations it's all happening at the
Active inference Institute slactive
infer an
repo everything we looked at is open-
sourced and pushed it would be awesome
for anyone to use play extend further
come
participate have fun all right thanks
bye